Ivan Dimitrov

ABOUT

I am a backend software developer who enjoys working in a high energy environment using modern technologies. I am used to applying agile methodologies, breaking down user requirements into tasks, teaching junior developers. Some of the technologies used daily are Golang, PostgreSQl, GraphQL and RESTFul services. I am familiar with git, docker, LaTeX and NoSQL databases as well. I am not afraid of making decisions and taking responsibility. I have also experience with enterprise projects using Java and Android.

SKILLS

Golang, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, RESTFul services.

Professional **EXPERIENCE**

StageAI, Sofia

Senior Software Developer

May 2020 - Present

- ▶ Breakdown tasks and requirements.
- ▶ Helping and teaching juniors colleagues.
- ▷ Supervise the working processes applying agile methodologies.
- ▶ Apply and encourage of using practices from 'Extreme Programming'.

Software Developer

Jan 2018 – May 2020

- ▷ Developed various web application using mainly with Golang, SQL and NoSQL dbs, REST and Graphql.
- ▷ Deliver high quality code using TDD.

Musala Soft, Sofia

Software developer

Aug 2016 – Dec 2017

▶ Worked as a contractor for Experian maintaining their existing project using mainly internal tools in the Java ecosystem.

Junoir Software Developer

Aug 2015 - Aug 2016

- ▶ Developed native android applications with Java.
- ▶ Maintained hybrid mobile applicatrion with Javascript and apache Cordova.
- ▶ Maintained Java enterpise application using JSP, maven, OracleDB.

Game developer-intern, Varna

Software Developer

Aug 2014 - Sept 2014

EDUCATION

Technical University, Varna

M.S of Computer Science Sep 2013 – June 2015 B.S of Electronics Sep 2009 - June 2013

CERTIFICATIONS Oracle Certified Professional, Oracle

Sep 2017

Agile Software Development, The Business Institute

Apr 2017

Managing Team Performance, The Business Institute

Feb 2017

Oracle Certified Associate, Oracle

Nov 2016